Where is Su Mu?
苏沐呢
Why is Lu Peng here?
陆鹏怎么来了
I thought he married the Princess Royal.
他不是跟了大郡主了吗
Yeah.
就是啊
Where is Su Mu?
苏沐在哪儿呢
Forget it.
别提了
The Princess Royal ignored him.
大郡主根本就不搭理他
She sent people to invite Su Mu from time to time.
反而隔三岔五地差人来请苏沐
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢
Coquettish.
风骚
A musician's manners.
乐人习气
What's wrong with being a musician?
乐人怎么了
You're a musician yourself.
你自己不也是乐人吗
I'm different from him.
我和他能一样吗
The Princess Royal picked me.
我是大郡主选中的
He only managed to use
他
his best musician's fame
不过是凭借花魁的名头
to enchant her for a while.
迷惑她一段时间
Now I've been engaged to her.
如今我都和她定亲了
And you're still pestering her.
你还阴魂不散地勾着她
She won't marry you.
她是不会跟你成亲的
A musician
乐人
doesn't deserve her.
配不上她
She's a cripple who can't walk.
她一个不会走路的残疾
She has no right to detest me.
她凭什么嫌弃我
Dare you say that
把你刚刚的话
again?!
再说一遍
I'm not saying it just because you told me to.
你让我说我就说呀
A musician
一个乐人
can't order me around.
还想命令我
After I get married,
等我大婚
I'll make you all fear me.
我要让你们所有人都怕我
The Princess Royal.
大郡主
I'll make the Princess Royal dote on me.
我要让大郡主宠爱我
Let me go.
放开我
All those who stand in the Second Princess's way
所有碍了二郡主路的人
must die.
都要死
Why are there still so many documents left?
怎么还有这么多
The City Owner's job is so tiring.
当城主好累啊
Take a rest if you are tired.
你要是累了 就歇歇
We can read these documents another day.
我们改日再看啊
That won't do.
那怎么行
Folk people have their problems
这百姓发生什么事情
and situations.
有什么情况
As the Crown Princess, I can't put them off.
我作为少城主怎么能拖延
I know.
我知道了
I miss you too.
我也很想你的
The mangoes and...
上次的芒果 还有
This is tiresome.
神烦
How come
你说这些官员
every official
她为什么每一个人
wrote crap?
写的都是废话
Have you finished carving the stamp?
章刻好了吗
Yes, I have.
好了
The City Owner's job is so tiring.
当城主真是太累了
I have to handle government affairs
不仅要处理公务
and guard against the hostile people from Xuanhu City.
这还要防止玄虎城的人来打我
Don't worry.
你放心
As long as I'm here,
有我在
Xuanhu City won't attack.
玄虎城不会出手的
This way is easier.
这样就省力多了嘛
Young Master, Your Highness.
少君 少城主
Lu Peng is dead.
陆鹏死了
Dead?
死了
He was found dead this morning
今早发现的
in an alley.
死在了巷子里
I knew he was cannon fodder.
我就说 他这是炮灰的命
Pushing him into the spotlight incurred heaven's punishment.
强捧遭天谴吧
Wait.
不对啊
I thought Lu Peng's death
陆鹏被杀的情节
had disappeared from the plot.
不是已经没有了吗
Why is the plot back on track?
剧情怎么又绕回来了
Is the plot still moving forward?
难道 剧情还在往下走
Masters.
先生
Didn't you say
你们不是说
a lot of things in the plot wouldn't happen?
很多情节不会发生了吗
But that musician still died.
可那乐人为什么还是死了
You said
您上回不还说
that musician was redundant.
这个乐人多余吗
Now you sound like
这 这怎么这回
you're reluctant to let him go.
又舍不得他了呢
I'm worried about Banana.
我担心的是香蕉
Have you noticed
你们有没有发现
that even though many things in the plot didn't happen,
虽然 很多情节没有发生
the fate of the characters had no change?
但人物的命运并没有改变
Banana didn't blow up the city.
香蕉没有炸城
But Apple's mother still fell ill.
但苹果的母亲还是一病不起
Crooked Melon didn't kill.
歪瓜也没有杀人
But that musician still died.
可那个乐人还是死了
I'm worried.
我很担心
I'm worried that Banana
我很担心香蕉也会像我
will end up like he did in the plot I wrote.
设计的剧情那样发展
Then how did Banana
那香蕉最后的命运
end up in the plot?
究竟是什么
According to the Crown Princess,
用少城主的话讲
Apple destroyed Banana.
是苹果灭了香蕉
What does destroy mean here?
那这灭了的意思是
Xuanhu destroyed Huayuan.
玄虎灭花垣
Han Shuo spared Chuchu for their love.
韩烁念及旧情放过楚楚
But he didn't know
却没想过
Chuchu would build up her strength
楚楚在苏子婴的辅佐下
and make a comeback with Su Ziying's help.
养精蓄锐 卷土重来
The two of them eventually had a showdown.
两人终决对战
Bai Ji!
白芨
Young Master.
少君
Forgive me for taking one step ahead.
我先走一步
When you occupied Huayuan City on the night of the Double Seventh Festival,
七夕之夜你攻占花垣城的时候
did you predict
可曾想过有朝一日
my return?
我会回来
I shouldn't have spared you back then.
当初我就不该心软放过你
Yes.
没错
That's your biggest mistake.
那是你犯过最大的错误
Unfortunately,
可惜
you have no chance to make amends.
你再也没有机会弥补了
Under these circumstances,
事到如今
only one of us
你我之间
can live.
只能活一个
Banana
这香蕉啊
can't resist the beauty eventually.
终究是英雄不过美人关
There's no beauty.
没有美人关
He's nowhere near Apple right now.
他现在跟苹果八竿子都打不着
The process doesn't matter.
过程不重要
What matters is the result.
重要的是结果
He won't confront Apple now.
他现在不跟苹果对峙
So he won't be stabbed in the heart.
自然也挨不到最后的穿心一剑
But I'm afraid.
可我就是害怕
I'm afraid that he'll end up like Orange's mother,
害怕他像橙子的母亲一样
like that musician.
像那个乐人一样
He may be able to avoid the stab,
虽然被刺的情节没有发生
but he'll still have the same ending.
但是结局还是一样
If he really dies,
那个时候他要是真的死了
what should I do?
我该怎么办
It's inevitable.
这也是难免的事
You designed him
那谁让你一开始
as a tragic character in the first place.
就把他设计成一个悲剧人物呢
Lin Qi, also known as Crooked Melon,
林七 也就是歪瓜
killed Lu Peng to save her black stone mine
为了保住自家乌石矿杀了陆鹏
and framed Han Shuo for the murder.
嫁祸给韩烁
Crooked Melon.
歪瓜
Have you done the job as I said?
让你办的事情怎么样了
I've paid the coroner
小人买通了验尸的仵作
to confirm the cause of Lu Peng's death.
核实了陆鹏的死因
We've secretly made a murder weapon that matches the wound.
已悄悄做出与伤口一致的凶器
But I don't understand
只是小人不懂
why you'd frame Han Shuo
小姐为何栽赃韩烁
for Lu Peng's death.
杀害了陆鹏呢
Han Shuo
这个韩烁
should be honored by Chuchu's affection.
楚楚能看上他 是给他脸
Who'd have thought that
没想到
he would love that useless Chen Qianqian?
他竟然喜欢陈芊芊那个废物
He made Minister Pei so mad
还气得裴司学
that Minister Pei left the clan school.
离开了宗学堂
However,
不过
Lu Peng died at the right time.
刚好这个陆鹏死得巧
I might as well seize the chance
我呢 刚好利用这个机会
to help Chuchu get even with him
给楚楚出口气
and
顺便
teach Chen Qianqian a lesson.
再教训一下陈芊芊
My lady,
小姐
Han Shuo is the Young Master of Xuanhu City.
可韩烁是玄虎城少君
Do you think the City Owner
杀个乐人
will punish him for killing a musician?
城主会罚他吗
Lu Peng was no ordinary musician.
陆鹏可不是一般的乐人
He was the Princess Royal's fiance.
他呀 是大郡主的未婚夫
Even if Han Shuo doesn't die this time,
这次韩烁就算是不死
he'll pay a grave price.
也得扒层皮
And he'd better be thrown
最好 是以戴罪之身
into the Music and Dance Academy as punishment,
罚进这教坊司
so I could discipline him.
让我亲自管教
By then,
到时候
I'd like to see Chen Qianqian's face.
我也好好看看陈芊芊的脸色
Have you got the things ready?
东西都准备好了吗
The murder weapon and physical evidence are ready.
凶器物证都已备好
Once your order is given,
只等你一声令下
those things will be sent to Young Master Han in Yueli Mansion.
想办法送入月璃府韩少君那儿
Good.
好
Let's do as planned tonight.
那今晚 咱们就按照计划行事
What are you planning to do tonight?
今晚你想做什么
Chen Qianqian?
陈芊芊
Why are you here?
你来干什么
I'm here to investigate a case.
我来查案啊
Lin Qi,
林七
don't assume that I don't know
你别以为我不知道
you killed Lu Peng.
陆鹏就是你杀的
You even intended to frame Han Shuo.
你现在还想栽赃给韩烁
Chen Qianqian,
陈芊芊
it's true that the two of us
虽然我们都希望
want each other dead,
对方比自己死得早一点
but you shouldn't
但是你也不用什么
blame me for everything.
都推到我身上吧
Quit making accusations without evidence.
空口无凭的
Where is your evidence?
证据呢
Search this place.
搜
Yes.
是
Don't move.
别动
The account book.
账簿
One chi long and three cun wide.
长一尺 宽三寸
According to the Criminal Minister,
这不是司刑查出来
it's the size of the weapon used to kill Lu Peng.
杀害陆鹏凶器的大小吗
Why did you draw this?
你们画这个做什么
For customization.
不定制吗
Your Highness.
少城主
How can you deny it now?
你还想怎么狡辩
The murder weapon is here.
凶器都准备好了
I... I made it for my own use.
那是 那是我做来自己用的
That's right.
那就对了
It's for your own use.
既然是你自己用的
And you killed Lu Peng.
说明陆鹏就是你杀的
Chen Qianqian, stop slandering me.
陈芊芊 你别血口喷人啊
Why would I kill Lu Peng
我好端端的
for no reason?
我杀陆鹏做什么
Why would I want to frame Han Shuo?
我 我诬陷韩烁做什么
(Han Shuo) The shingle.
花牌
You even made the shingle.
花牌也都做好了
Are you waiting for Han Shuo to hang out the shingle
你是不是就等着韩烁
at the Music and Dance Academy tomorrow?
明天到教坊司来挂牌了
You dare to touch my man.
敢动我男人
Arrest her.
抓起来
Chen Qianqian.
陈芊芊
The whole Huayuan City doesn't belong to you
你别以为现在城主不理事
even if Her Majesty isn't taking charge.
整个花垣城就是你的天下了
You are right.
你说对了
Huayuan City belongs to me now.
花垣城现在就是我的天下
You should know who Han Shuo is.
你也不看看韩烁是什么人
How dare you touch him?
你就敢动他
You won't get to frame Han Shuo.
韩烁是你能陷害的吗
You have no regard for human lives.
如今你还敢草菅人命
Take her away and lock her up.
拉下去 关起来
I'll decide her punishment.
听我发落
Chen Qianqian, I thought you changed.
陈芊芊 我以为你变了
But you're still that rascal.
你还是这么无赖
You... You are settling the case?
你 你办案
Why don't you investigate first?
你都不查一查吗
Those storytellers were right.
先生说得对
Lin Qi really did it.
果然是林七干的
Things didn't turn out
原来故事的情节
as the plot designed.
没有按照原剧情的轨迹推动
I just didn't know
只是我不知道
Lin Qi was playing tricks in the dark.
林七在背后搞小动作
Now I can rest easy.
这样我就放心了
I heard
小人听闻
Chen Qianqian searched the Music and Dance Academy.
陈芊芊搜教坊司
So I went there to watch the disturbance.
就过去围观了好大一场骚乱
Lin Qi?
林七
What trouble has she caused this time?
她又惹什么乱子了
Chen Qianqian found the weapon used to kill Lu Peng
陈芊芊在林七小姐那里
at Miss Lin Qi's place.
搜到了杀害陆鹏的凶器
Lin Qi
这个林七
always does more harm than good.
成事不足 败事有余
Everyone knows she is close to me.
人人都知道她与我交好
She shouldn't have interfered.
她偏在此时蹚这趟浑水
If she isn't cautious enough,
一个不小心
she'll make me look suspicious.
岂不是又把嫌疑引回到我身上了
If the Lin family withdraws her statement,
如果林家要翻供
the case will definitely be investigated thoroughly.
必彻查此事
Maybe we should
您看 要不要彻底坐实了
prove Miss Lin Qi guilty
林七小姐的罪名
to close Lu Peng's case.
好了结陆鹏这件事
Your Highness, it's just my idea.
郡主 这都是小人的主意
It has nothing to do with you.
与您无关
Lin Qi of the Music and Dance Academy
关于教坊司林七
murdered the Princess Royal's fiance Lu Peng
杀害大郡主未婚夫婿陆鹏
and attempted to frame the Crown Princess's husband Han Shuo.
企图嫁祸少城主夫婿韩烁一案
How are you going to handle the case?
该如何处置
Miss Lin Qi
林七小姐
is the only daughter of the Lin family, after all.
她毕竟是林家唯一的女儿
No matter who pleads for her,
不管谁为她求情
I won't spare her.
我都不会放过她
Even Chuchu can't change my mind.
二姐也不行
Please sentence Lin Qi
请少城主
to death.
治林七死罪
Death?
死罪
Wait.
不对啊
I killed off Lin Qi in the plot.
林七也被我写死了
Sentencing her to death
她如果真判了死罪
only proves
不刚好证明了
that I can't change the fate of the characters
即使改变了剧情
even though I've changed the plot.
我也无法改变人物的命运吗
Then Han Shuo will...
那韩烁岂不是
Must not die.
不能死
Lin Qi must not die.
林七不能死
Lin Qi has made mistakes.
林七虽有过错
But considering the Lin family
但念在林家
has served Huayuan City for years,
为花垣城效忠多年的分儿上
I'll spare her life for now.
暂且留她一条性命
I handled the case on impulse yesterday.
其实我昨日也是冲动型办案了
I didn't carry out a thorough investigation.
没有好好地彻查
We have testimony and physical evidence.
人证物证皆在
What's the need for investigation?
还查什么案
Your Highness,
敢问少城主
did Lin Qi attempt to frame Han Shuo?
林七 是不是想栽赃韩烁
Yes.
是
Did Lin Qi's weapon
林七的武器
match the weapon used to kill Lu Peng?
是不是和杀害陆鹏的凶器一致
Yes.
是
As the Crown Princess,
你身为少城主
you surely can convict the owner
难道还不能定一个
of the Music and Dance Academy.
教坊司掌柜的罪吗
You've been friends with Lin Qi for many years.
二姐与林七多年情谊
You two even called each other sisters yesterday.
昨日还以姐妹相称
How come you want her dead today?
为何今日句句就让她死
I'm judging the case as it stands.
我只是就事论事
You're too emotional
是少城主你
while handling affairs.
太感情用事了
Shouldn't you be grounded?
你不是在关禁闭吗
Why are you here?
为何出现在这里
It concerns Lin Qi.
事关林七
To maintain Huayuan City's law,
为维护花垣城法度
of course I should set an example,
我自然要身先士卒
lest you show mercy
免得少城主因为我的缘故
to a criminal for my sake.
对罪人法外开恩
You want her dead so badly?
你就非要让她死吗
Your Highness, make a decision.
少城主做个决断吧
What should we do about Lin Qi?
如何处置林七
Lin Qi, you have a visitor.
林七 有人来看你了
Chuchu?
楚楚
It must be hard for you
真是难为你
to come here to have a good laugh at me.
竟然跑到这儿来看我笑话
You're
你呀
pampered, overweening,
娇生惯养 目中无人
and conditioned to act willfully.
任性惯了
Change yourself.
以后改改吧
Are you calling me willful?
你说我任性
Seriously?
我没听错吧
Who snatched a groom on the street,
是谁当街抢婚
stole the Dragon Bone and released the mountain bandits?
盗取龙骨 放走山贼
In terms of willfulness,
要论起任性
Chen Qianqian.
没人敢认第一
I don't understand.
我真是不明白了
Why have you always been playing against me?
你为何事事都要跟我作对啊
Because you always play against Chuchu.
谁让你总跟楚楚过不去
You stole Chuchu's stuff.
你抢了楚楚的东西
And I'll steal the stuff back for her.
我就要替她抢回来
I know
我知道
you grew up with Chuchu.
你同楚楚一起长大
Compared to me, you are more like her sister.
比我与她更像姐妹
But you should know that
但你知不知道
people can change.
人也是会变的
Bullshit.
你放屁
At this point,
都这个时候了
you're still sowing discord.
你还敢挑拨离间
You think Chuchu is heartless like you?
你以为楚楚会像你一样心狠手辣
Perhaps you killed Lu Peng
说不准就是你杀了陆鹏
and framed me.
然后栽赃给我
Fine.
行
Fine. I did it all.
行 都是我做的
Maybe it can make you feel better.
也许这样你还能好过点
I
我
planned to sentence you to death.
原本是要处死你的
Chuchu kept begging me
是楚楚不停地求我
to spare your life.
让我网开一面留你一命
Alright?
行了吧
I knew it.
果然如此
Your life can be spared, but you can't escape punishment.
死罪可免 活罪难逃
I'll banish you.
我判你流放
To what place?
去哪儿
A good place.
好地方
Xuanhu City.
玄虎城
Where men take charge?
男人当家做主的地方
You might as well kill me.
你还不如杀了我
With this golden token,
有了这块金牌
you won't be stopped by anyone in Huayuan City.
花垣城境内没有人敢为难你
You're banishing me to Xuanhu City.
你都把我流放到玄虎城了
What's the use of Huayuan City's golden token?
还给我一块花垣城的金牌做什么
You think I'm stupid
你当我傻呀
and I should thank you?
还要谢谢你
Are you sure you don't want it?
确定不要
Lin Qi,
林七
you are getting banished.
你都快被流放了
This is the most valuable thing you could have.
这是你从头到脚最值钱的东西
At least you can trade it for food.
好歹还能换个吃食
It's made of pure gold, after all.
毕竟是纯金的
You don't want it?
不要
Whatever.
不要拉倒
Stop!
你站住
Why hasn't Chuchu visited me?
楚楚为什么一直不来看我
I grounded her.
我关她禁闭了
She pestered me and pleaded for you every day. It was so annoying.
每天都来烦我向我求情 烦死了
I'd rather not see her.
眼不见为净
Chen Qianqian! You jerk!
陈芊芊 你浑蛋
You... You should come at me.
你 你有什么事你冲我来
Set Chuchu free!
你把楚楚放了
Let Chuchu go!
你放了楚楚
Chen Qianqian!
陈芊芊
I've finally saved Lin Qi's life.
总算是保住林七的性命
As long as Lin Qi is safe,
只要林七没事
Han Shuo should be safe.
韩烁应该也不会有事
According to the original story line,
这按照原来的故事线
the ending is around the corner.
马上就要大结局了
If nothing happens
只要这段时间
during this time,
不会发生什么事
everything is going to be fine.
一切都会顺利的
Lately, it's been found that the envoys of Xuanhu City
最近发现玄虎城使者
and their men have been lurking on the borders of Huayuan City,
及手下潜伏在花垣城边境
ready to make moves.
蠢蠢欲动
Please take a decision as soon as possible.
请城主早做决断
Xuanhu City's envoys haven't left.
玄虎城使者居然没有走
Did they know about mother's critical illness?
难道他们知道了母亲病危的消息
What's on your mind?
想什么呢
Nothing.
没什么
I know
我知道
you're stuck between Xuanhu City and Huayuan City
你夹在玄虎城和花垣城中间
and things are difficult for you.
很为难
I'll send them a letter
我这就传信
to tell them that Huayuan City has no weakness
告诉他们花垣城毫无破绽
and they shouldn't stay here for long.
不宜久留
They'll be back soon.
他们很快就会回去的
Don't worry.
你放心
As long as I'm in Huayuan City,
只要我在花垣城一天
the two cities won't make war
就不会发生两城交战
and the people won't live in misery.
民不聊生的场面
Will you always stay in Huayuan?
那你会一直留在花垣吧
This question never crossed my mind.
我没想过这个问题
I was just asking.
我也就是随口一问
We can talk about our future later.
以后的事情以后再说
We are like an ink pad and a stamp.
就像印泥和印章
Without the ink pad, the stamp
印章如果没了印泥
is an useless rock.
就是块废石
Without the stamp, the ink pad
而印泥如果没了印章
is an ordinary pigment.
也就是普通的颜料
They are like you and me.
就像你和我
They'd never separate.
永远不会分开
Your Highness.
少城主
What's the matter?
怎么了
It's late. Go to bed.
时间不早了 你早点休息啊
Mind your own business.
你自己睡你自己的
Stop paying attention to my sleep.
你管我睡不睡
Your Highness, I have important news for the Young Master.
少城主 我有要事向少君禀报
No matter what it is, leave it for tomorrow.
有什么事 明天再说
Nobody must disturb us here.
这里不许再有任何人来打扰
Alright.
好嘞
Now,
那
nobody will disturb us again.
现在不会有人来打扰我们了
Let's
我们
carry on.
继续
Your Highness.
少城主
Your Highness, Miss Lin Qi has set off.
少城主 林七小姐已经上路了
As you ordered,
属下按您的吩咐
I have asked the City Guards to take care of her on the way.
托随行的护城军照顾她
You didn't have to tell me that.
这个事情有必要跟我讲吗
I'm not close to her.
我跟她玩得很好吗
What's the deal now, my lady?
你又怎么了 大小姐
I can't keep on walking.
走不动了
We have not gone far.
这才走了多远
You'd spend ten days to complete a three-day journey.
三天的路你走了十天
You're going so slowly,
照你这速度
when will we arrive in Xuanhu City?
我们猴年马月才能走到玄虎城啊
I'm not going.
我就是不走了
What can you do to me?
你能拿我怎么办啊
You two can go without me.
要不然你们两个走
It's okay. It's okay.
没事 没事
She's just tired.
累了好说好说
We'll continue our journey after a rest.
我们歇会儿再走
Release me from the shackles.
赶紧给我解开
If our superior hadn't
要不是上边的人
ordered us to take care of you,
吩咐我们照顾你
we wouldn't have cared about your feelings.
谁管你这么多事
The Second Princess ordered you to take care of me.
二郡主吩咐你们好好照顾我
So you have to take care of me.
你们就得好好照顾我
Otherwise, I'll write a letter to Chuchu
要不然等我到了玄虎城
after arriving in Xuanhu City,
给楚楚写封信
asking her to kill you two.
让她要了你们俩的命
The Second Princess?
二郡主
The Second Princess wasn't the person who ordered us.
嘱咐我们的人不是二郡主啊
Yeah.
对
Not Chuchu?
不是楚楚
Is it the Princess Royal Yuanyuan?
那难不成是大郡主沅沅
It's the Crown...
是少城
Chen Qianqian?
陈芊芊
You are Chuchu's subordinate.
你是楚楚的人
I want to see Su Mu.
我要见苏沐
Your Highness,
大郡主
the Music and Dance Academy
我们教坊司
is going through big changes
发生这么大的变故
in utter chaos.
乱成一团
Your timing is unfortunate.
您来的时间真是不凑巧
I want to see Su Mu.
我要见苏沐
But we are closed.
可我们已经歇业了
Do you want to drink?
大郡主这是想饮酒了
Or do you want music?
还是想听曲了
We musicians of the Music and Dance Academy
我们这些个教坊司乐人
are highly skilled
个个技艺精湛
and able to serve you well.
定能服侍好大郡主
I waited for you in my mansion every day.
我日日在府中等你
You didn't show up.
你不来
I had no choice but to come here and look for you.
我就只好来这里寻你
I see. You want to have fun
原来是大郡主
in the Music and Dance Academy.
想逛教坊司了
You once said
你曾说过
the Music and Dance Academy's beauty
教坊司春色十分
mostly manifested in you.
你独占八分
The service of all musicians
众乐人百般讨好
couldn't outdo your hearty smile.
也不及你的倾心一笑
Why would you rather have other people keep me company
为何你宁愿别人陪伴我
than smile at me?
也不肯对我笑
I'm willing to serve
苏某
the dignitaries and nobles in Huayuan City.
宁愿服侍花垣城达官显贵
But I'm unwilling to associate
但却不愿再与大郡主
with you.
有半分瓜葛
Zi Nian.
梓年
Escort the Princess Royal back to her mansion.
送大郡主回府
Your Highness.
郡主
I'll be here tomorrow.
我明日还来
If you don't change your mind,
你若不肯改变心意
I'll choose another one of these musicians
我便从这些乐人中再选一个
as my husband.
与他成婚
We dare not marry you.
不敢啊不敢
Your Highness, please spare us.
大郡主 您饶了我们吧
We dare not follow in Lu Peng's footsteps.
万万不敢步陆鹏的后尘
What are you doing?
干吗
Extend your hand.
把手伸出来
I have something for you.
我有东西给你
What is it?
什么
Me.
我呀
I carved a new stamp for you.
我给你刻了枚新的章子
Heart-shaped.
爱心
Good to see you smile.
你笑了就好了
You've been feeling distraught these days.
你最近总是心神不宁的
What happened?
发生什么事了
Is it about
是
the City Owner's illness?
城主的病
Or is it about the annoying government affairs?
还是政事烦心
Maybe,
或者
too many unforeseen events have happened recently.
是最近变故太多了
Lu Peng died.
陆鹏虽然死了
But there's still a barrier
但是苏沐跟沅沅中间
between Su Mu and Yuanyuan.
总是隔着一层
I really don't understand.
我是真的不明白
How nice it would be
在感情里面
if two people in a relationship were open and honest.
两个人都开诚布公的该多好
Why must they
为什么非要
make one-sided sacrifices
你为了我 我为了你
for each other's sake?
单方面的付出
It only hurts them.
虐人虐己呢
If you really think so,
如果你真这么想
then let's make a deal.
那咱们说好了
No matter what happens in the future,
以后无论遇到任何事
you must not make decisions alone
你都不能像苏沐一样
like Su Mu.
自己做决定
We should talk things out.
咱们有商有量
If you make this deal with me,
你如果答应我
I'll go with you and try to talk some sense into Su Mu.
我就陪你去劝苏沐
Even if I have to tie him up
我就算是把他绑了
and put a blade on his neck,
就算把刀架在他脖子上
I'll make him accept the marriage.
也得让他答应这门婚事
I'll make this deal with you.
我答应你
We'll come up with solutions together.
我们一起想办法
And I want you to promise me one thing.
那你也要答应我
No matter what happens in the future,
以后不管遇到任何事情
we won't hide things from each other or lie to each other.
我们都不可以隐瞒 欺骗对方
Okay?
好不好
Wait.
等一下
Nobody will disturb us now.
现在没有人打扰我们了
Your Highness!
少城主
Bad news! Lin Qi is dead!
不好了 林七死了
The story is about to end.
故事现在都已经快说完了
You can't change Banana's fate now.
你现在要改香蕉的结局
Banana was destined to die.
这香蕉注定是要死的
If you wanted to change it,
你这要改
you would need to start from the beginning.
那除非从头改起
Start from the beginning?
从头改起
I shouldn't have written the wedding scene where the groom was taken.
怪就怪我不该写抢亲那场戏的
It's karma at work.
都是报应
But Orange
可是橙子
should have been dead long ago.
不也说是早该死的人吗
She has lived to this day.
她不也活到了现在吗
Your Highness,
少城主啊
let's be honest,
咱平心而论
is this Orange
现在的橙子
still the same Orange?
还是原来的橙子吗
I see.
我明白了
I set the trap.
虽然局是我设的
But now I'm involved.
但是我现在在局中
I've lost control of many aspects.
所以很多事情就控不住了
To protect him
如果想要保他
from his original fate,
回避掉之前的命运
I have to push him out.
就得给他送到局外
After all, the outsiders are the safest.
毕竟局外人才是最安全的
I'll change Banana's fate.
我要给香蕉逆天改命
Then Banana will end his part in the story earlier.
那这是让香蕉提前结束故事啊
It won't do.
这不行啊
From Orange's perspective,
这么做对于橙子来说
this story won't be a comedy anymore.
那 就不是喜剧了呀
Even in those so-called comedies,
所谓喜剧
reality always contradicts hopes.
总是离不开事与愿违
That's why people say "great joy leads to sadness."
所以才有乐极生悲一说
Even the happiest ending
哪怕是再一团和气的结局
can include happy tears.
恐怕也免不了喜极而泣
Tragedy and comedy
这悲剧和喜剧
have always been sharing the same root.
本来就不分家
In that case,
那 这样一来
Banana will only know
香蕉只知其一
part of the truth.
而不知其二
He'll hate Orange very much.
他会恨死橙子的
Yeah.
是啊
When heaven is about to confer a great responsibility on any Orange,
天将降大任于橙子也
it'll remove Orange's skin and seed,
必定扒其皮 去其籽
cut Orange into four pieces and extract Orange's juice.
切成四瓣 榨成汁
Happiness only comes after suffering.
才能苦尽甘来
It's the hardship
这也是橙子
Orange must endure.
必须经历的磨难
Your Highness, where are you going?
少城主 这是准备去哪儿啊
I'll go find Pei Heng and Su Mu.
去找裴恒跟苏沐
The screenplay has been completed.
剧本都写好了
It's time to bring in the actors.
就该请演员了
Your Highness.
少城主
I need to adjust my mode.
我调整一下模式
I'll be shooting a heart-breaking scene soon.
这马上进入苦情戏了
Are you scared by what happened to Lin Qi?
是被林七的事吓到了
You've been spacing out all day.
今天一整天都魂不守舍的
Here.
来
Calm your nerves.
压压惊
It's not about Lin Qi.
不是林七
It's about Yuanyuan and Su Mu.
是沅沅跟苏沐
If I put myself in their shoes
其实换位而居
as the Young Master
如果在玄虎城
of Xuanhu City
我身为玄虎少君
who fell for a courtesan
看上一风尘女子
and insisted on marrying her,
硬要娶她
the people of Xuanhu City would judge me.
定是会被玄虎城的百姓说三道四
Su Mu's concern
苏沐的担忧
isn't groundless.
不无道理
He really is thinking for Yuanyuan,
他确是为了沅沅着想
fearing that others might attack her for this.
怕她落人口实
Since you know where the problem lies,
少君既然知道了问题出在哪里
you should try to talk some sense into Su Mu.
不如去劝劝苏沐
I made an appointment with him
我约了他
in the tea house.
在茶楼见
Okay.
好
I'll go there in your stead.
我代你赴约
And I'll visit mother in the City Owner's mansion.
那我去城主府 看看母亲
Alright.
行
Zi Rui.
梓锐
Your Highness.
三公主
Let's go find Pei Heng.
我们去找裴恒
You're treating Young Master Han like this again.
你又这样对待人家韩少君
Have you forgotten about the erotic pictures?
你忘了上次春宫图的事了
Actually,
其实啊
it's not a big deal
咱背地里去找裴公子
seeking comfort from Mr. Pei secretly.
那都没什么
After all, it's a mistake every woman makes.
毕竟这是你们女人都会犯的错误
But you've got to toughen up.
可你倒是硬气点呀
When Young Master Han found out,
人家韩少君稍微知道点风吹草动
you knelt on the ground right away.
你就咣当一下往地上一跪
You even pulled me down with you.
你还拉着我一块
You weren't honorable at all.
你太不争气
Weak legs don't matter.
腿软倒不是什么大事
I'm afraid things will be different this time.
只怕这次
He'll not only scold me,
他不仅要骂我
but also take a blade to kill me.
还要提刀来砍我了
Qianqian, you wanted to see me?
芊芊 你找我
Pei Heng, I need to ask you a favor.
裴恒 我有一件事想求你帮忙
I'd do anything for you.
刀山火海 在所不辞
Mr. Su, sorry for keeping you waiting.
苏公子 久等了
I just arrived.
我这也是刚到
Where is the Crown Princess?
少城主呢
She's taking care of the City Owner.
她在照顾城主
And she couldn't leave for now.
一时抽不开身
So she asked me to come in her stead.
特让我代为赴约
Who's in that room?
那包厢里面是谁呀
Young Master Han and Su Mu.
是韩少君跟苏沐
Your Highness, you should go back.
大郡主 你还是回吧
He still refused to see me?
他还是不肯见我吗
It's not that Mr. Su refused to see you.
不是苏公子不见你
He went out to meet Young Master Han
是他昨天出去见了韩少君之后
and didn't return the whole night.
就彻夜未归
He didn't return the whole night?
彻夜 未归
Yeah.
是啊
Where can he be?
你说他会去哪儿呢
We musicians
我们做乐人的
have nowhere to go
除了教坊司
except the Music and Dance Academy.
也没别的去处了
I hope that he hadn't ended up like Lu Peng.
可别是和陆鹏一样了
Su Mu has gone missing?
苏沐失踪了
The Criminal Minister is on this case.
司刑大人已经查办了
The last victim Lu Peng
上次死的那个陆鹏
also came from the Music and Dance Academy.
也是教坊司的
I have a feeling that he has been sexually assaulted.
怎么感觉被劫色了
Who did it
到底是谁下的手啊
before I could do it?
怎么比我还快
(Man Lost) My dear Mr. Su.
我的苏郎啊
Still worrying about Su Mu?
还在担心苏沐的事
It's my fault.
怪我
After meeting him in the tea house yesterday,
昨天与他茶馆相会后
I didn't send him back to the Music and Dance Academy.
没将他送回教坊司
I'm a little scared.
我有点害怕
Of what?
你怕什么
Mother had an accident and slipped into a coma.
母亲突发意外 昏迷不醒
Su Ziying attempted to harm me,
苏子婴意图害我
but then disappeared.
却如今下落不明
Lu Peng walked on the street
陆鹏好端端地走在路上
until his throat was cut open.
却被人抹了脖子
Not to mention Lin Qi.
林七就更不用说了
Huayuan City hasn't been peaceful lately.
花垣城最近不太平
The City Guards are controlled by Chuchu.
护城军又在楚楚手上
You can't stay with me around the clock.
你总不能十二个时辰都陪着我吧
When you aren't with me,
那万一你不在
who will keep me safe?
谁保护我
Don't think wildly.
别胡思乱想
I've sent people
苏沐的事
to investigate Su Mu's case.
我已经派人去查了
Did you bring some shadow guards
你从玄虎城过来
when you came from Xuanhu City?
是不是有一支暗影
Are you using them to probe and pass on messages.
你是用他们来传递查探消息的吗
Bai Ji.
白芨
Why do you guard against me?
你这么防着我做什么
I'm not asking the Young Master
我又没向你们家少君
for the guards.
索要这支卫队
I can let you have them.
也不是不给你
It's just...
只不过是
It's just I don't know Kung Fu
只不过是现在
to protect myself right now.
我是没有武功傍身
If I knew Kung Fu, I wouldn't be afraid of robbers and bandits.
要不然我也不怕这些强盗匪徒
If they dared come,
他们要是敢过来
I'd take their lives.
竖着过来 我让他们横着过去
Unfortunately,
只可惜
one cup of poisoned wine
当时的一杯毒酒
dissolved my Kung Fu which I had been practicing for over ten years.
化去了我苦练十几年的功夫
Young Master, this isn't wise.
少君 这恐怕不妥
This is your...
这是你
This is the only token that can order my guards.
这是能调动我护卫的唯一信物
They'd risk their lives to protect the token's owner.
他们会誓死保护令牌的主人
Now
现在
it's yours.
交给你了
For real?
真给我了
I asked you for it and you just gave me.
我要你就给我了
The guards
这支卫队
are your only trump in Huayuan City.
可是你在花垣城唯一的底牌了
Now you let me have this token.
你把这个给我了
What if... What if I don't deserve it?
万一 万一我不值得呢
Of course you do.
你当然值得
I gave you my possessions and life.
只是我将身家性命都给你了
But I don't hear anyone calling me husband.
还听不到一句夫君
Husband.
夫君
What did you call me?
你叫我什么
Alright.
好了
Let's go find Su Mu.
我们还是快点去找苏沐吧
I'm worried about him.
我还是挺担心他的
Only by pushing Han Shuo out of the story completely,
只有让韩烁在故事里彻底消失